[{"question": "Which is the first search engine of the internet?", "options": ["A. Yahoo", "B. Wais", "C. Archie", "D. Mozilla"], "answer": "C. Archie"}, {"question": "In a Database Management System(DBMS) the content and the location of data is identified by ?", "options": ["A. Subdata", "B. Sequence Data", "C. Beta Data", "D. Meta Data"], "answer": "D. Meta Data"}, {"question": "'.MOV' extensions refer to which kind of file?", "options": ["A. Image file", "B. Movie File", "C. Audio File", "D. ZIP File"], "answer": "B. Movie File"}, {"question": "----- is used to realocate exexutable program to main memoryduring execution", "options": ["A. linker", "B. compiler", "C. interpeter", "D. loader"], "answer": "D.loader"}, {"question": "---- is used to translate a program written a high level language into a equivalent machine code.", "options": ["A. compiler", "B. linker", "c", "D. both A and B"], "answer": "A. compiler"}, {"question": "operator with the same precedence are evaluated in which of the following orders", "options": ["A. left to right", "B. right to left", "C. unpredictable", "D. none of above"], "answer": "A. left to right"}, {"question": "which keyword is used for function ?", "options": ["A. fun", "B. define", "C. def", "D. function"], "answer": "C. def"}, {"question": "which of the following in the use of function in python ?", "options": ["A. function are reusable pieces of program", "B. function do not provide better modularity for your application", "C. you cannot create your own function", "D. all the mention"], "answer": "A. function are reusable pieces of program"}, {"question": "which of the following command will create a list", "options": ["A. list = list()", "B. list = []", "C. list = list([1,2,3])", "D. all the mention"], "answer": "D. all the mention"}, {"question": "suppose the list example is ['h','e','l','l','o'] what is the len(list example)", "options": ["A. 5", "B. 4", "C. 6", "D. error"], "answer": "A. 5"}, {"question": "which of these about a frozen set is not true", "options": ["A. mutable data type", "B. allow duplicate value ", "C. data type with unorder value", "D. immutable data type"], "answer": "A. mutable data type"}, {"question": "set member must not be hashable", "options": ["A. true", "B. false", "C. error", "D. none of above"], "answer": "B. false"}, {"question": "what is the data type of(1)", "options": ["A. tuple", "B. integers", "C. list", "D. both tuple and integers"], "answer": "B. integers"}, {"question": "identify the compiler c of unix", "options": ["A. gcc", "B. cc", "C. borland", "D. vc++"], "answer": "B. cc"}, {"question": "choose the invalid predefined macro as per ANSI C", "options": ["A. file", "B. time", "C. data", "D. c++"], "answer": "D. c++"}, {"question": "choose the correct statement that can be retrieve the remainder of the division", "options": ["A. rem = modf(5.5%1.3)", "B. rem = modf(5.5,1.3)", "C. rem = fmod(5.5,1.3)", "D. rem = f(5.5,1.3)"], "answer": "C. rem = fmod(5.5,1.3)"}, {"question": "similarity between a structure ,union,enumeration.", "options": ["A. all the helpful in defining new variable", "B. all the helpful in defining new data type", "C. all the helpful in defining new pointer", "D. all the helpful in defining new structure"], "answer": "B. all the helpful in defining new data type"}, {"question": "the maximum combined of the length of the command line argument as well the spaces between adjacent argument is a)120 character,b)56 character,c)vary from one os to another", "options": ["A. a", "B. a,b", "C.  a,b,c", "D. c"], "answer": "D. c"}, {"question": "in c parameter always ", "options": ["A. passed by value", "B. pass by reference", "C. pass by value result", "D. none of above"], "answer": "A. pass by value"}, {"question": "which of the following is true about return type all function in c", "options": ["A. function can return any type", "B. function can return any type except array and function", "C. function can return any type except function and union", "D. function can return any type except array and pointer"], "answer": "B. function can return any type except array and function"}, {"question": "consider a boolean function of n variability.the order of an algorithim that determine whether the boolean function produces a output.", "options": ["A. logarthmic", "B. linear", "C. quardatic", "D. exponential"], "answer": "D. exponential"}, {"question": "in order traversal of binary search tree will produce.", "options": ["A. unsorted", "B. reverse of input", "C. sorted", "D. none of above"], "answer": "C. sorted"}, {"question": "what data structures is used for depth first traversal a graph", "options": ["A. queue", "B. stack", "C. list", "D. none of above"], "answer": "B. stack"}, {"question": "which of the following algorithm is not stable", "options": ["A. merge sort", "B. quick sort", "C. bubble sort", "D. insertion sort"], "answer": "B. quick sort"}, {"question": "which of the below given sorting techniques has highest best case run time complexty", "options": ["A. quick sort", "B. selection sort ", "C. insertion sort", "D. bubble sort"], "answer": "B. selection sort"}, {"question": "which of the following algorithm cannot design without recursive", "options": ["A. tower of hanoi", "B. fibonacci series", "C. tree traversing", "D. none of above"], "answer": "D. none of above"}, {"question": "if the locality is a concern you can use ---- to traverse the graph", "options": ["A. breadth first search", "B. depth first dearch", "C. either bfs to dfs ", "D. none of above"], "answer": "B. depth first search"}, {"question": "which of the following is not possible with an array on C programming language", "options": ["A. decleration", "B. definition", "C. dynamic allocation", "D. array of string"], "answer": "C. dynamic allocation"}, {"question": "graph traversal is different from a tree traversal because", "options": ["A. tree are not connected", "B. graph may have loops", "C. tree have root", "D. none is true is a subset of graph"], "answer": "C. tree have root"}, {"question": "what is abstract class", "options": ["A. a class must contain all pure virtual function", "B. a class must contain at least one pure virtual function", "C. a class may not have contain pure virtual function", "D. a class must contain pure virtual function define outside the class"], "answer": "B. a class must contain at least one pure virtual function"}, {"question": "which of the following is not keyword in c++", "options": ["A. volatile", "B. friend", "C. extend", "D. this"], "answer": "C. extend"}, {"question": "escape the sequence character '10' occupies --- amount of memory", "options": ["A. 0", "B. 1", "C. 2", "D. 4"], "answer": "B. 1"}, {"question": "what is generic class", "options": ["A. function templates", "B. class templates", "C. inherit class", "D. none of above"], "answer": "B. class templates"}, {"question": "the default executable generation of unix for a c++ program is", "options": ["A. a.exe", "B. a", "C. a.out", "D. out.a"], "answer": "C. a.out"}, {"question": "which of the following is true ", "options": ["A. all object of a class share all data member of class", "B. object of a class do not share non static member every object has it own body", "C. object of a class do not share code of non static method they have their own copy", "D. none of above"], "answer": "B. object of a class do not share non static member every object has it own body"}, {"question": "a member function can always acess the data is", "options": ["A. the class of which it is number", "B. the object of which it is a number", "C. the public part of its class", "D. the private part of its class"], "answer": "A. the class of which it is number"}, {"question": "if a function is friend of a class which of followiwith", "options": ["A. a function can only be declare by a friend by a class itself", "B. friend function are not member of a class they are associated with it", "C. friend function are member of class", "D. it can have access to all member of the class even private ones"], "answer": "C. friend function are member of class"}, {"question": "which of the following is false about references in c++", "options": ["A. reference cannot must be null", "B. a reference must be intialize when declare", "C. once a reference is created , it cannot be created be later made to references a object .it cannot be reset", "D. reference cannot refer to constant value"], "answer": "D. reference cannot refer to constant value"}]